In this clip, we're going to talk about, you know, different sort of safety gear that you can use to make sure that your time out on the water while you're kite surfing is going to be much more safe and, you know, definitely friendly if some sort of thing goes wrong.
Basic things like helmets and impact vests are going to make your day a lot better in the event that you crash or wipe out pretty hard.
You're going to be using a board and sometimes you could be kiting in shallow water, so you know helmet an absolute must if you?re trying, you know, learn a new trick, you're just getting into the sport or you feel like, you know, it's an overpowering conditions and you might just want a little extra protection.
Some people think that they look a little nerdy but, you know, you have new style of helmets with, you know, a brand that looks pretty cool.
And don't be that guy that who doesn't want to wear some king of safety gear just because you don't think you look cool.
On, you know, this impact vest here, it can be a bit of a pain because you know a feature like this, a clip or a zipper, can get kind of in the way when you're using it with your harness, but let it be known, we're doing all these tricks these days that are throwing you into the water sometimes at high speeds and you have no control of how you're going to land.
And these whole things right here, the ribs, don't feel too good when they're broken.
So, right here, an impact vest that's going to keep you from doing that.
So, also, it's going to provide you a little flotation and, you know, it's just kind of comfortable.
So, impact vest and helmet, wear them, especially when you're a beginner.